<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Sirwan Afifi</title><description>Sirwan Afifi&apos;s blog</description><link>https://sirwan.info/</link><language>en-us</language><item><title>How I Use Obsidian to Publish Posts</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/how-i-use-obsidian-to-publish-posts/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/how-i-use-obsidian-to-publish-posts/</guid><description>Obsidian has become a key part of my daily routine—it&apos;s one of those apps I always keep open on my computer. While I started using it for journaling, planning tasks, and reviews, it has now become my main tool for writing blog posts too.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Advent of Code 2024</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/advent-of-code-2024/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/advent-of-code-2024/</guid><description>As we approach Advent of Code 2024, I wanted to share my experience from previous years tackling these coding challenges with perhaps an unconventional choice of tools: PowerShell and Pester. While PowerShell is often pigeonholed as just an automation tool, I&apos;ve found it to be a surprisingly powerful language for algorithmic problem-solving, thanks to its foundation on .NET and its expressive pipeline syntax.</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Microsoft.Extensions.AI</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/microsoft-extensions-ai/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/microsoft-extensions-ai/</guid><description>With .NET 9.0, a new set of abstractions has been introduced to simplify integrating AI into applications: `Microsoft.Extensions.AI`. This package offers a consistent programming model by wrapping various AI providers (such as OpenAI, Azure OpenAI, and Ollama), allowing .NET developers to work seamlessly with different models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Git Commits as Documentation (RAG-Powered Commit Search)</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/git-commit-as-documentation/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/git-commit-as-documentation/</guid><description>If you know me, you know that I love Git, and I believe if you use it right, it can be a powerful tool not only as a version control system but as a documentation tool. With Git, we basically document our code changes over time.</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Weekend with Chrome AI</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/weekend-with-chrome-ai/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/weekend-with-chrome-ai/</guid><description>Building a Chrome extension to summarize web pages</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>HTML Parser and Whitespace</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/html-parser-and-whitespace/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/html-parser-and-whitespace/</guid><description>The HTML parser treats whitespace characters between elements as text nodes</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>موختەسەر لە بارەی موهیم بوون نووسین بلاگ</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/ku/importance-of-blogging/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/ku/importance-of-blogging/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Local AI Models in Browsers (Chrome Canary)</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/local-ai-models-in-browsers/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/local-ai-models-in-browsers/</guid><description>Browsers and operating systems are increasingly expected to have access to language models. This could really boost productivity, making tasks like translation and summarisation a lot easier.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My Approach to Problem Solving - Blazor Version</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/my-approach-to-problem-solving-blazor-version/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/my-approach-to-problem-solving-blazor-version/</guid><description>Here&apos;s how I tackle my programming tasks using Test Driven Development (TDD). I first try to understand the problem and then break it down into smaller tasks. TDD helps me do this effectively. I don&apos;t use TDD just to write tests; it&apos;s a way to manage and solve problems step by step.</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Azure API Management</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/azure-api-management/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/azure-api-management/</guid><description>I have been playing around with Azure API Management lately and really like it. It&apos;s a great way to manage your APIs, essentially serving as an API Gateway to handle incoming API calls and route them to various backend services. The backend service could be any HTTP API, WebSocket, GraphQL, Azure Function, Azure App Services, etc.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Redis RESP</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/redis-resp/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/redis-resp/</guid><description>RESP (REdis Serialization Protocol) is a binary protocol that Redis uses to communicate with clients. It is a simple protocol that is easy to implement in any programming language. This means that we can communicate with Redis over a socket connection. For instance, here is a naive implementation in C# that sends a command to Redis and reads the response:</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Securing Next.js Apps Using Microsoft Identity Platform</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/securing-next.js-apps-using-microsoft-identity-platform/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/securing-next.js-apps-using-microsoft-identity-platform/</guid><description>In a previous article, I explained how to secure a Blazor application using the Microsoft Identity Platform. In this article, I will demonstrate how to secure a Next.js application. The process is almost identical in terms of the steps required on the Azure portal; however, the implementation differs.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Securing Blazor 8.x Web Apps Using Microsoft Identity Platform</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/securing-blazor-8.x-web-apps-using-microsoft-identity-platform/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/securing-blazor-8.x-web-apps-using-microsoft-identity-platform/</guid><description>Implementing authentication and authorisation is always a bit of a headache. There&apos;s always those edge cases you forget about when doing it yourself. It&apos;s smarter to let a third-party service handle Identity and Access Management stuff. Azure&apos;s got you covered with Microsoft Entra ID (you might know it as Azure AD).</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond Titles, Embracing Data Analysis in Every Tech Role</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/beyond-titles-embracing-data-analysis-in-every-tech-role/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/beyond-titles-embracing-data-analysis-in-every-tech-role/</guid><description>I use LLMs daily for a wide range of activities, including personal and work projects, as well as for my blog. They help me automate tasks, analyse data, and make decisions, thereby simplifying my life and enhancing work efficiency. Last week, my boss requested a report on our current status, including areas where we are investing more time and money. I had already developed a system to send daily log reports to his email following each stand-up meeting with my team. However...</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Weekend with Swift</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/a-weekend-with-swift/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/a-weekend-with-swift/</guid><description>Every Friday night I try to do something to get my dopamine flowing to start my weekend. Programming is one of the things that does the work for me and increases my dopamine level so much that if I start focusing on something, nothing can distract me. I can keep going for hours after hours without feeling tired, which sometimes isn&apos;t good. We should definitely pay attention to our health and get out of the building to connect with real people instead of just sitting in front of the computer coding...</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Programmers and LLMs</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/programmers-and-llms/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/programmers-and-llms/</guid><description>If you&apos;re a programmer like me, you might also like making things easier by [automating stuff](https://automatetheboringstuff.com/). This isn&apos;t about being lazy; it&apos;s about being efficient. For instance, when I&apos;m shopping at [Tesco](https://www.tesco.com/), which is my go-to supermarket in the UK because it&apos;s cheaper and right next to my house, I always think about how I can speed up the shopping process. Usually, I rely on a shopping list, but it&apos;s time-consuming, especially because I need to carefully check nutrition labels, and what I buy varies depending on things like gym days or cheat meal days.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Migrating to Astro</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/migrating-to-astro/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/migrating-to-astro/</guid><description>Astro is a new kind of static site builder that delivers lightning-fast performance by bringing together the best of modern build tools like React and GraphQL, and serverless deployment with Vercel. In this post, we&apos;ll walk through how to migrate an existing MDX blog to Astro.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Quick Note</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/a-quick-note/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/a-quick-note/</guid><description>My colleague was assigned a task in which he had to set up open-source software on one of our servers. The process was a bit tricky, making the installation challenging, so he was somewhat disappointed to not finish his task. This is one of those moments when you want to fix a problem, but so many things happe</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>آشنایی با TypeChat</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/typechat/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/typechat/</guid><description>در دنیای Generative AI مفهوم Prompt نقش خیلی مهمی را ایفا میکند؛ چون برای گرفتن یک خروجی با کیفیت میبایست یک ورودی یا Prompt با کیفیت و خلاقانه داشته باشیم؛ این قضیه به قدری اهمیت دارد که یک عنوان شغلی هم برای آن در نظر گرفته شده است Prompt Engineer؛ چون اگر یک Prompt به خوبی نوشته نشود، نتایج غیرواقعی و نادرستی میتواند تولید کند که به این رفتار [Hallucination](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallucination_(artificial_intelligence)) یا Fabulations گفته میشود.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>iPhone</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/iphone-theft/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/iphone-theft/</guid><description>On April 30, 2023, I was out with my friend, and we were traveling back home from London Waterloo to Guildford. We had to wait a couple of hours for the train to Guildford, so we decided to pass the time by traveling back and forth from Waterloo to the Northern line. While on the tube, both of us fell asleep, and my phone was on my lap...</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visualising Your IoT Data</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/visualising-your-iot-data/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/visualising-your-iot-data/</guid><description>Recently, I&apos;ve learned a lot about the Internet of Things (IoT) and I just gotta share some of the cool stuff I&apos;ve found. I&apos;m using the ESP32 module to gather data from a temperature sensor and humidity sensor. I&apos;ve used the Arduino IDE before, ..</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Different ways of adding your signature on a PDF</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/different-ways-of-adding-your-signature-on-a-pdf/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/different-ways-of-adding-your-signature-on-a-pdf/</guid><description>My coworker wrote some Python code to add a signature on PDFs. Since Python isn&apos;t my thing, I wrote the same code in a few of my favorite languages. Probably because I haven&apos;t used Python in production or because of its wired syntax (Maybe I only like curly-brace languages). Anyway, here&apos;s the Python code I mentioned:</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>انجام یک تسک ساده با Golang</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/web-automation/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/web-automation/</guid><description>یکی از کارهای خسته‌کننده برام web automation هست؛ ابزارهای زیادی برای این کار توسعه داده شدن معروفترین‌هاش Puppeteer، Playwright هستن. برای یک پروژه نیاز بود یک فرآیند رو به صورت headless انجام بدم؛ چون با این دو ابزار زیاد کار کرده بودم تصمیم گرفتم با یک چیز متفاوت جدید تسکم رو انجام بدم بنابراین پروژه رو با Golang شروع کردم و از go-rod استفاده کردم.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>بررسی خطای undefined is not iterable در JavaScript</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/undefined-is-not-iterable/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/undefined-is-not-iterable/</guid><description>Iteratorها این امکان را به ما میدهند که بر روی یک مجموعه iterator کنیم؛ به شرطی که مجموعه iterable باشد؛ در JS مقادیر زیر iterable هستند به این معنا که میتوانیم آیتم‌ها را یکی یکی پیمایش کنیم:</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blazor Meetup</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/blazor-meetup-reading/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/blazor-meetup-reading/</guid><description>On May 4, 2022, I attended a meetup at one of Microsoft&apos;s campuses in Reading. This was my first time at a meetup like this. It was about Blazor on .NET 6 presented by Steve Sanderson. I was already familiar with him from his previous work Knockout, which was/is an MVVM framework designed for the web. These days, I mostly build web applications using Node.js/React. In addition, I have been looking at Blazor...</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>نکات Golang</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/golang-basics/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/golang-basics/</guid><description>مدتی است در حال یادگیری Golang هستم. Golang یک زبان statically complied است که توسط Google توسعه داده شده است. اینجا نکاتی که در مورد Golang یاد میگیرم رو سعی میکنم به صورت پراکنده به اشتراک بذارم.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>تولید فایل‌های PDF توسط React</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/generating-pdf/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/generating-pdf/</guid><description>تهیه فایل PDF تا حدودی چالشی است به خصوص زمانیکه بخواهیم یکسری کامپوننت ری‌اکتی را تبدیل به PDF کنیم؛ در یکی از پروژه‌هایمان امکان تهیه فایل PDF را در اختیار کاربران قرار داده‌ایم. روال کار به این صورت است که ابتدا کاربر با کلیک روی یک باتن یک گزارش تهیه میکند سپس کاربر باید امکان پیش‌نمایش گزارش را نیز داشته باشد. تا اینجای کار خبری از PDF و تولید PDF نیست و چیزی که به کاربر نمایش داده میشود یکسری کامپوننت ری‌اکتی هستند که درون یک مودال پشت سر هم نمایش داده میشوند. درون هدر این مودال یک باتن جهت دانلود گزارش به صورت PDF را داریم؛ مشکل از آنجایی شروع میشود که این کامپوننت‌ها باید با همان کیفیت یا به اصطلاح به صورت pixel perfect به PDF تبدیل شوند و سپس روی دیسک ذخیره شوند.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ذخیره فایل CSV در SQL Server</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/importing-csv-file-in-sql-server/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/importing-csv-file-in-sql-server/</guid><description>سری قبل در مورد ذخیره کردن یک فایل CSV توی دیتابیس MySQL توضیح دادم. در ادامه نحوه ذخیره یک فایل CSV در SQL Server رو بررسی میکنیم. برخلاف MySQL در SQL Server استوریج انجینی برای فایلهای CSV تعبیه نشده و خودمون باید فایل CSV رو بخونیم و بعد ذخیره کنیم. برای اینکار ابتدا نیاز به نصب SQL Server روی macbookم داشتم در نتیجه از داکر برای اینکار استفاده کردم</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>آشنایی با CSV Storage Engine در MySQL</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/csv-storage-engine/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/fa/csv-storage-engine/</guid><description>MySQL از چندین Storage Engine پشتیبانی میکند؛ Storage Engine در واقع کامپوننت‌های MySQL هستند که عملیات SQL را بر روی جداول میسر میکنند. </description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Showing Topbar Progress Indicator in React</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/showing-topbar-progress-indicator-in-react/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/showing-topbar-progress-indicator-in-react/</guid><description>I use circular loading indicators in my React applications before data is returned from the server...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using Mirage With Vite</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/using-mirage-with-vite/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/using-mirage-with-vite/</guid><description>Recently, I have been using Vite and liked it quite a bit. It&apos;s an extremely fast build tool, If you haven&apos;t checked it out, you should definitely do so. Although it was developed by Evan You, it can be used for React, Svelte, and more...</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Web Server Logs</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/web-server-logs/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/web-server-logs/</guid><description>An important part of managing software applications effectively is keeping logs, because they provide information about the server&apos;s performance and activity and can indicate any issues. An application&apos;s behavior has to be analyzed in order to track events and debug any issues...</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>disallow nested ternary expressions (no-nested-ternary)</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/no-nested-ternary/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/no-nested-ternary/</guid><description>We usually use ternary operator as a shortcut for `if` statement, For instance, in React applications we can use them to conditionally rendering elements inline...</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OS Notification</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/OS-Notification/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/OS-Notification/</guid><description>I recently tweeted something about a little script I had put together to automate one of the tasks I had always struggle with. I thought it would be a good idea to share the process in a little bit more detail:</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MySQL - Transforming JSON data into relational tables</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Transforming-JSON-data-into-relational-tables/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Transforming-JSON-data-into-relational-tables/</guid><description>MySQL provides some built-in functions to work with JSON data. One of which is JSON_TABLE which maps JSON data into a temporary relational table.</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting Started With Sequelize</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/getting-started-with-sequelize/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/getting-started-with-sequelize/</guid><description>Sequelize is an Object Relational Mapper (ORM) which enables us to query and manipulate data stored in a relational database. There are several ORM for Node.js out there...</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WebSocket and React</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/WebSocket-and-React/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/WebSocket-and-React/</guid><description>WebSocket is a communication protocol. It&apos;s bidirectional in nature which means that either client or server can send data at any time. With WebSocket, we can build applications such as multiplayer games, ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Displaying Secured Images</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Displaying-Secured-Images/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Displaying-Secured-Images/</guid><description>Ran into an interesting problem this week with displaying secured images on the page. The problem is that `img` tag doesn&apos;t show the image if the resource is secured with a token or a username/password...</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MobX with React and TypeScript</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/MobX-with-React-and-TypeScript/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/MobX-with-React-and-TypeScript/</guid><description>MobX is one of the popular state management libraries. One of the great things about MobX is that we can store state in a simple data structure and allow the library to take care of keeping everything up to date.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Server-Sent Events and React</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/%20Server-Sent-Events-and-React/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/%20Server-Sent-Events-and-React/</guid><description>Server Sents Events are realtime events sent from the server to the client. It&apos;s a way to subscribe to a data stream sent by a server. Basically, it is a long-running HTTP connection with a particular mime type.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Setting Up Tailwind</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Setting-Up-Tailwind/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Setting-Up-Tailwind/</guid><description>Tailwind is a utility-first CSS framework for rapidly building custom user interfaces.</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Passing custom HTTP Header via Apollo Client</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Passing-custom-HTTP-Header-via-Apollo-Client/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Passing-custom-HTTP-Header-via-Apollo-Client/</guid><description>Today I wanted to send along an array as a parameter with all queries from client to server. But I wanted to find a quick way to accomplish the task as changing all queries took a tremendous amount of time. One thing that came to my mind was making use of ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Redux</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Redux/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Redux/</guid><description>Redux is a predictable state container for JavaScript apps.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Initializing state using class field declaration</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Initializing-state-using-class-field-declaration/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Initializing-state-using-class-field-declaration/</guid><description>If you want to initialize state in a class based component we have two options: In constructor As a class property</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Flux</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Flux/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Flux/</guid><description>A design pattern developed at Facebook to keep data flowing in one direction (unidirectional data flow)</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Ionic React App</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Building-Ionic-React-App/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Building-Ionic-React-App/</guid><description>Ionic is a cross-platform mobile app development framework built on top of Angular. It allows you to build mobile apps using web technologies like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript...</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Testing React Components</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Testing-React-Components/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Testing-React-Components/</guid><description>Testing React components is a crucial part of the development process. It helps us to make sure that our components are working as expected.</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Higher-Order Components</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Higher-Order-Components/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Higher-Order-Components/</guid><description>Higher-Order Components are a great way to share common functionality between components without repeating code.</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Importing JSON files into SQL Server</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Importing-JSON-files-into-SQL-Server/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Importing-JSON-files-into-SQL-Server/</guid><description>I was assigned to a task to import a GeoJSON file into a SQL Server database. The file was pretty big; I couldn&apos;t even open the file in an editor. At first, I wanted to write a simple program (with C# or Python) to open the file and then loop through the entries, ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using IHostingEnvironment in a test project</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Using-IHostingEnvironment-in-a-test-project/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Using-IHostingEnvironment-in-a-test-project/</guid><description>Assume that you have a service which accepts IHostingEnvironment as its dependency...</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Migrating To Gatsby</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Migrating-To-Gatsby/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Migrating-To-Gatsby/</guid><description>I&apos;ve been playing around with Gatsby, and so far I&apos;m quite happy. It&apos;s basically a framework based on React and GraphQL that makes it easy to create both website and web applications.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Morse code</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Programming-challenges-morse-code/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Programming-challenges-morse-code/</guid><description>Morse Code is a set of dots and dashes (short mark, dot or &apos;dit&apos; (·) and longer mark, dash or &apos;dah&apos; (-)). Basically, it&apos;s a character encoding scheme for transmitting cryptographic messages which used in telecommunication. Think of it as the early version of texting. ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Calling Stored Procedures using Dapper</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Calling-Stored-Procedures/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Calling-Stored-Procedures/</guid><description>Today I wanted to call a Stored Procedure using Entity Framework Core. It is possible using DbSet.FromSql() method, which is one of the powerful features of Entity Framework Core. It gives us the ability to run RAW SQL queries directly against a database...</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Highlighting Current Link in Razor Pages</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Razor-Pages-Highlight-Current-Link/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Razor-Pages-Highlight-Current-Link/</guid><description>Let&apos;s say you have several pages in your Razor Pages application. Now you want to make the menu items active depending on the page you are currently on...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Passed Exam 70-483 - Programming in C#</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Passed-Exam-70-483-exam/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Passed-Exam-70-483-exam/</guid><description>I have been developing with C# for a while, and I decided to pass Exam 70-483 in order to validate my skill. In order to pass the exam, you should be able to perform the following skills:...</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hosting React app on IIS</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Hosting-react-app-on-iis/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Hosting-react-app-on-iis/</guid><description>Today I wanted to host a React application; the first and easiest option was hosting the app using a package called serve which is basically a static file serving tool. The process was easy, all I had to do was first prepare a production build of my application using npm run build then run the npx serve command inside my build&apos;s directory...</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hosting a WCF Service as a Windows Service Using Topshelf</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Hosting-WCF-Service/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Hosting-WCF-Service/</guid><description>You might be wondering why I am blogging about WCF. Is it still relevant? This is part of a legacy WCF project, and I am responsible for adding some functionalities to it, I like it though. By the way, it&apos;s been a long time since it went out of fashion, but many large enterprise applications still use it.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What&apos;s Elasticsearch</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/What&apos;s-Elasticsearch/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/What&apos;s-Elasticsearch/</guid><description>Elasticsearch is a search engine based on the Lucene library. It provides a distributed, multitenant-capable full-text search engine with an HTTP web interface and schema-free JSON documents.</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GraphQL</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Graphql/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Graphql/</guid><description>Recently I have been working on a node stack project as a full stack JavaScript developer, it&apos;s a great experience because I&apos;m working with talented developers. We use TypeScript on both backend and frontend which is great because I&apos;m coming from a .NET background and couldn’t be happier; Well we have types for our JS code :) ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>React Hooks</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/React-Hooks/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/React-Hooks/</guid><description>Hooks are a new feature that is coming up in React v16.7.0-alpha, it&apos;s a really great feature, I am so excited about this new feature. The goal is to use all functionalities you can ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahriban - My first Hackathon project (Challenges, Lessons Learned)</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Shahriban/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Shahriban/</guid><description>As you probably know, Hackathon is an event that programmers, designers, entrepreneurs to get together for a short period of time to collaborate on a project. The cool part of this event is delivering tasks rapidly, In fact, it&apos;s more like a Marathon for programmers. I have never participated in a hackathon ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Uploading file in Vue.js</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Uploading-file-in-Vue.js/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Uploading-file-in-Vue.js/</guid><description>In this blog post I am going to show you how you can upload file using Vue.js. On the backend we will use ASP.NET Core MVC to expose an endpoint to the client to receive file.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TypeScript and Vue.js</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/TypeScript-and-Vue.js/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/TypeScript-and-Vue.js/</guid><description>In this blog post I would like to show how to combine Vue.js with TypeScript inside an ASP.NET Core 2.x application.</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing Console-based UI in CSharp</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Developing-Console-based-UI-in-C/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Developing-Console-based-UI-in-C/</guid><description>Console Applications don&apos;t have graphical user interface or GUI. Instead, they run from Command Line, for example instead of writing a name into a textbox and clicking a button we would instead invoke the Console Application and provide the name as a parameter. ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Does making decision matter?</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Does-making-decision-matter/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Does-making-decision-matter/</guid><description>We make decision all the time, most of these decisions are done unconsciously, others we agonize over, we all have been there agonizing over a difficult or big decision, we always worry about what to do next, in fact we are trying to make the right decision, ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Running PowerShell on macOS</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Powershell-on-macOS/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Powershell-on-macOS/</guid><description>It&apos;s been a while I have been using macOS as my primary operating system, you can read about my expreince here. Today I wanted to run a PowerShell script, I searched around and figured out Microsoft has made PowerShell open source open source and the ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SQL Server on Linux in Docker on a Mac</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/SQL-Server-on-Linux-in-Docker-on-a-Mac/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/SQL-Server-on-Linux-in-Docker-on-a-Mac/</guid><description>Over the last few months, I have been working on a couple of ASP.NET Core projects, it&apos;s been great experience so far becuase I can easily work on different platforms while working on these projects. I recently bought a MacBook Pro and have decided to do .NET projects on macOS since then...</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Working remotely</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Working-remotely/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Working-remotely/</guid><description>It has been 8 months and so that I have been working remotely for a startup out there. It&apos;s been my pleasure to work with a team of great and talented members. over the past few months, I have learned a lot both in terms of technical stuff and working as a team member.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My first experiences with Linux</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/My-first-experiences-with-Linux/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/My-first-experiences-with-Linux/</guid><description>Running Window 98 on my PC was my first experience with Windows. in fact, for the last 11 years or so, Windows has been the dominant operating system that I&apos;ve been using. So, up until now, I have been an avid fan of Windows.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Environments in ASP.NET Core</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Environments-in-ASP.NET-Core/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Environments-in-ASP.NET-Core/</guid><description>In ASP.NET Core we can have different hosting environments, this is supported by an environment variable called ASPNETCORE_ENVIRONMENT. You can see this value is already set to Development:</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting to know Singleton pattern in C#</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Getting-to-know-Singletone-Pattern/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Getting-to-know-Singletone-Pattern/</guid><description>This pattern helps us to ensure a class has only one instance. The term comes from the mathematical concept of a singleton...</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Designing Fluent Interfaces in C#</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Designing-Fluent-Interfaces-in-C/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Designing-Fluent-Interfaces-in-C/</guid><description>The concept of Fluent Interface was coined by Martin Fowler to create various objects and wire them up together. This pattern is often used for object configuration and setup.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Explicit Interface Implementation</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Explicit-Interface-Implementation/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Explicit-Interface-Implementation/</guid><description>Explicit interface implementation is a way to implement interface members that allows you to implement interface members with the same name.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Delegates in C#</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Delegates/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Delegates/</guid><description>Lately I have been studying some topics in C# in order to improve myself. I think Delegate is one of those topics which is kinda difficult for beginners to initiate with. So, in order to make it clear how it works, I&apos;m going to make some explanations in this post.</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thinking out of the box to become a better programmer</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Thinking-out-of-the-box-to-become-a-better-programmer/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Thinking-out-of-the-box-to-become-a-better-programmer/</guid><description>Today I was talking with a friend of mine about thinking, The topic is interesting and I wanted to share it with you because as a programmer we are always thinking and trying to find solutions.</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why AngularJS?</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Why-Angular/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Why-Angular/</guid><description>I wanted to share a few thoughts about AngularJS</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Asynchronous Execution in JavaScript</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Asynchronous-Execution-in-JavaScript/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Asynchronous-Execution-in-JavaScript/</guid><description>As you know browsers are typically single threaded, It means that the browser can only be doing either update the UI or executing JavaScript at any given time. It actually incapable of doing theme simultaneously.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Object Oriented JavaScript Part 2</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Object-Oriented-JavaScript-Part-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Object-Oriented-JavaScript-Part-2/</guid><description>In this post we are going to talk about classes in JavaScript and how they are different from classes in other languages.</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Object Oriented JavaScript Part 1</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Object-Oriented-JavaScript-Part-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/Object-Oriented-JavaScript-Part-1/</guid><description>In this post we are going to talk about object oriented programming in JavaScript and how it&apos;s different from other languages.</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My first blog post!</title><link>https://sirwan.info/blog/en/First-Blog-Post/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sirwan.info/blog/en/First-Blog-Post/</guid><description>Here&apos;s my first blog post :) In this blog I&apos;m going to share thing that I learn, hope you enjoy reading my blog :)</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>